We will continue with the time, complexity and let's introduce that logarithmic time complexity of
log and.
Algorithm brands and proportionally to that logarithmic of that input size.
Let's take an overview about the graph of the logarithmic y equal log X in the blue and white equal
limb x in Iran.
We are interested in studying the Log X.
So, or like Logan, this is the same concept.
So.
As we see the algorithm, an algorithm run in a proportional to the logarithmic of the input sites,
for example, our cars are ordered and split into two parts.
If I told you.
Go and get that 10 of the spades if we are working with the linear and they are ordered.
I'm telling you that it is ordinary.
So in case of linear, I need to go all of these passing through these 13 plus 13 plus 13.
They are equal to 39 and still reaching 10.
So I am going to search about 48 cards to reach that.
But in case of logarithmic time complexity.
I am going to divide this deck into two main parts, the first part it will include.
There.
Diamonds and the clubs, and the second part will includes the hearts and the spades.
So I I'm going to search for the 10th then spades and they are ordered.
Deck of cards.
So I decided to separate their cards.
All the cards to two main parts.
The first part contains the diamonds and the second part contains diamonds and clubs, and the second
part contains the heart and spades.
Remember, I am searching for the dance of the spade, then spade.
So automatically, I'm not going to search in this first part because the spades are in the second part.
I have removed half of these cards.
They are 52.
I have removed 26 cards.
Now, if they are ordered in the same the same way as picture being told us or showing us, I can remove
all their dead things because spades are there.
That is so black, so I removed that red.
Their hearts.
So the spades are now 13, I have removed till now, 26 plus 13 as equal to 39.
I decided to split it since they are ordered.
I decided to get rid of half of these cards because the 10 is the half of the 13 is seven.
The six point six point five.
So I removed six cards.
I have now seven eight nine 10 J Q and OK.
Now I need again to get half a get rid of half of these paper cards, so I removed these three because
then now is that middle and I get this in this way, I am one more time we will divide into two and
we can see that the ten in the middle element.
Okay.
So we are not looking through all the elements of this car of these cards.
We are not searching one by one, one by one by one for for these cards.
We are just eliminating half.
Every time we eliminate half of these half of these cards in order to get a certain level.
Okay, so this time complexity is a logarithmic time complexity.
OK.
Now.
Let's go to that code.
We have an algorithmic complexity, an example of a flawed loop that it is going to prison system that
out the print hello.
But this time it's very different.
You see, guys, I.
And it will start from Wuhan and stops at KNH, but this time it would that the iteration will be increased
every time by city.
So every time I will jump through and add three, so if I have.
Thirty I entered and equal to 30.
OK, this loop will print system that hollowed out that print.
Hello.
OK, so this slope will not the print, the times the Hello.
OK.
It will print ten times because.
We have and now is what the third and every time I is at it three times, so it's start by one one plus
three is equal to four now and equal to four.
But it is the first iteration and printing the hello.
Only one time I becomes equal to four and I becomes seven, then I becomes 10.
So these are the iterations through and equal to 30.
This is very important because we are not going through every element we are of n because M from one
to 30, we are jumping at the third level and the third number every time we are skipping two numbers
and adding the third one.
OK.
So the total time here is all lug and this is the time complexity for this example, in the loop, while
we have adding I plus three, the third type of time complexity is the quadratic time complexity all
of and square represents an algorithm whose performance is directly proportional to the square size
of input date.
Think about it as linear, but it's a square.
So for example, if we have a card deck here and I told you to pick the first card, you will pick the
ace of
clubs and I told you get all cards with the same number.
So you are going to search all the deck for the Aces.
OK.
So you search all the aces here.
Ace of Diamond, ace of clubs and ace of diamonds and hearts and spades.
OK.
These are the four cards.
OK, so you every time you are searching for a card for Ace and Diamond, you looked through all the
cards, OK?
And then you are going to search for a heart.
So you loop all the the hearts and the spades.
So we are picking a specific card with a specific number among all of the cards.
So.
If we are choosing only one card, it will be a linear.
But if we are choosing a specific number that can be all the cards, all cards with the same number,
we are using a quadratic time complexity in terms of coding the.
The running time of Lou is the running time of the statement inside the the loop, including tests multiplied
by the number of iterations.
Let me show you this example.
We start from here.
This is a loop.
Having a complex.
Having end times.
OK, but in your mind that we are going to loop through this red one and times?
OK.
And we have here a for loop and having also and so this is a nested loop and we are going to look through
this green one, green statements and times.
So every we are going to loop and times in the red and every time we are, we loop inside and there
and we are going to execute and times the green one.
So this will be printing if we are entering five here and equal to five.
So an equal to five, I will go and loop five times this loop.
And this will also printing hello five times every time it will be executed.
So five times five is equal to twenty five times.
So therefore we have the total time here since we have learned that system that out print.
This is not this is not real.
It's not related to any input of the user, which is RN.
So it is a constant so this constant time.
This constant time and.
Blue correspond to see.
OK.
And and this and in.
And Green refers to this and that.
The inner loop inside the outer loop, and this will be referring to the outer loop.
OK, so.
The outer loop is n multiplied by the inner loop and and this statement is constant, so it will result
in C and Square.
And since we have one term and we took the highest, the highest degree and the constant is removed,
so it will result in all.
And square.
So this is the time complexity of the quadratic.